Finding Aid for John B. Lansing papers, 1957-1970
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
John B. Lansing papers 1957-1970
Lansing, John B.
851669 Aa 2
Professor of economics and program director of the Institute for Social Research at University of Michigan. Professional correspondence, 1965-1969, research files relating to the study of the economics of transportation, and miscellaneous report studies.
4 linear feet
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was the gift of Mrs. John B. Lansing (donor no. 4976 ) and came to the library in 1980.
Periodic additions to the records are not expected.
The collection is open to research.
John B. Lansing was born in Geneva, NY on July 11, 1919. He received his doctorate in economics from Harvard in 1949, then came to the University of Michigan where he taught in the department of economics until his death in 1970. He became full professor in 1962 and chairman in 1970. In addition, Lansing served as program director of the University's Institute for Social Research. Lansing's area of expertise was the economics of transportation and travel and how transportation impacts on residential patterns and urban mobility. He died September 8, 1970.
The collection is arranged into two series. Professional papers consists largely of correspondence, 1965 to 1969. There was no correspondence prior to 1965. The second series is a Topical File relating to his research and to his study of transportation issues.
Subjects:
Economics.; Social surveys--Research.; Transportation.; University of Michigan. Dept. of Economics.; University of Michigan--Faculty.; University of Michigan. Institute for Social Research.; Lansing, John B.
- Professional papers
  - Bibliography and curriculum vita (Box 1)
  - Correspondence 1965-1969 A-Z
    - 1965 A-Z, 16 folders (Box 1)
    - 1966 A-Z, 13 folders (Box 1)
    - 1967 A-Z, 12 folders (Box 1)
    - 1968 A-Z, 9 folders (Box 1)
    - 1969 A-Y, 15 folders (Box 1)
- Topical files 1957-1970
  - American Association for the Advancement of Science (Box 2)
  - Barton, Charles H. (Box 2)
  - Birmingham, University of (Box 2)
  - Boeing--667-20--Distance and Mode (Box 2)
  - Brown, Robert. Department of Commerce (Box 2)
  - Building Research Advisory Board, National Academy of Science, 5 folders (Box 2)
  - Chain of Moves (Box 2)
  - Civil Aeronautics Board, 5 folders (Box 2)
  - Commerce Department, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Committee on SST Sonic Boom (Box 2)
  - Computer Service Advisory Committee, 6 folders (Box 2)
  - Cost of Data Collection (Box 2)
  - Doxiadis (Box 2)
  - Dygert, Paul (Box 2)
  - Dynamar (Box 2)
  - Eastern Airlines (Box 2)
  - Economics Department. Industrial Organization; Field Personnel (Box 2)
  - Education. Study Proposals (Box 2)
  - Field costs (Box 2)
  - Ford Foundation 1966, Housing and the Urban Environment (Box 2)
  - Ford Motor (Box 2)
  - Geographic Mobility Fall 1966, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Health, Education and Welfare. Field Reader. (Box 2)
  - Highway Research Board
    - General (Box 2)
    - Proposal 1965 (Box 2)
    - Paper 1966 (Box 2)
    - Individual Transportation Study 1967, 4 folders (Box 2)
    - Transportation Attitudes 1968 (Box 2)
  - Income and Wealth Conference, 5 folders (Box 3)
  - Income and Wealth. Paper on Wealth for January 1967, 6 folders (Box 3)
  - Income and Wealth. Cohorts 1968 (Box 3)
  - Institute du Transport Aerien, 3 folders (Box 3)
  - Location Variable. Study 706, 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Location Variable. Study 707, 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Maynes, E. Scott (Box 3)
  - Michigan Ports (Box 3)
  - Milwaukee Analysis, 4 folders (Box 3)
  - Noise (Box 3)
  - Nystuen, John D. (Box 3)
  - Parker, John (Box 3)
  - Polk, Lon, 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Population Association. Atlantic City April 1969 (Box 3)
  - Port of New York Authority (Box 3)
  - Port of New York Authority. Project 702, 4 folders (Box 3)
  - Prelims (Box 3)
  - Public Roads 1966-1967, 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Rackham Fund. ISR 765 (Box 3)
  - Residuals (Box 3)
  - Salaries 1967 (Box 3)
  - Science Information Exchange (Box 3)
  - Social Science Research Council, 3 folders (Box 3)
  - State Highway Officials Car Use, 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Statistical Standards (Box 4)
  - Survey of Consumer Finances. Vacation Trips 1961 (Box 4)
  - Survey of Consumer Finances Analysis 1962, 4 folders (Box 4)
  - Travel. 744 (Box 4)
  - Travel. Summary and Analysis. 728 (Box 4)
  - Transportation. Notes, Reading, 3 folders (Box 4)
  - Transportation. Research paper 1967 (Box 4)
  - Transportation Department, 6 folders (Box 4)
  - United Nations (Box 4)
  - Urban Mobility (Box 4)
  - Visitors (Box 4)
  - Miscellaneous
    - 1957 undated (Box 4)
    - 1960-1965 (Box 4)
    - 1966-1970 (Box 4)